Ultimately, war is its generals.
（王騎(おうき)）結局 戦は武将のものです
呉慶(ごけい)さんは 戦を
理詰めの盤面と捉えていますねえ
Wu Qing is treating the war as a game board of logic.
一方 麃公(ひょうこう)さんの戦は
燃え盛る ひとつの大きな炎
On the other hand, Biao Gong's war is one big blazing flame.
（信(しん)）アア…
理解できませんか？ ンフフフッ…
Don't understand?
呉慶さんも
麃公さんの戦を理解できません
Wu Qing cannot understand Biao Gong's way of war either.
But neither can Biao Gong
しかし 麃公さんも―
呉慶さんの軍略を
見切っているわけではありません
see all of Wu Qing's strategy.
Which is right?
どちらが是か
Which is wrong?
どちらが非か
これは どちらか一方の首が
飛ばねば 分かりかねますねえ
We can't know unless one of their heads goes flying.
Ancient China.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望が解放されていた
human desire was unleashed.
激烈なる戦争と戦乱の嵐が―
And a storm of violent wars lasting a monumentally long 500 years erupted all across China.
500年という
途方もなく長きにわたって―
中国全土に吹き荒れていた
Desire, pleasure, pain, fear.
欲望 快楽 苦痛 恐怖…
過酷で絶望に満ちた その世界には
竜がいたに違いない
With that world filled with such relentless despair, it was as though a dragon had invaded.
“時代”という名の竜が
A dragon called the era.
そして
竜の炎に焼かれるかのように―
And as if burned by the flames of a dragon,
over one hundred states were destroyed, one by one, until only seven were left standing.
100を超える国は 次々と滅び
今や ７国に淘汰(とうた)されていた
Yan, Qi, Zhao, Wei, Han, Chu...
燕(えん) 斉(せい) 趙(ちょう) 魏(ぎ) 韓(かん) 楚(そ)…
そして 秦(しん)である
and Qin.
The seven great powers, in order to devour each other,
７つの大国は おのおのが
おのおのを食らい尽くすように―
took up their swords of desire and continuously pieced the throats of enemy states.
欲望の剣を 敵国の喉元に向かって
突き立て続けた
The world knew it as the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
世にいう春秋戦国時代である
そして今 西の果て 秦の国から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the state of Qin in the far West.
大きな歴史の風が
吹き荒れようとしている
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
これは
戦乱の時代を走り抜いた―
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
Timing
G_I_A
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
The Meaning of General
（じい）左方向から敵！
Enemy's coming from the left!
（じい）5,000から6,000！
Five to six thousand!
Biao Gong, eh?
（呉慶）麃公か… 愚かな
The fool!
この呉慶の軍に奇襲は通用せぬ
No surprise attack will make it through the Qu Qing Army.
（兵士たち）オオッ！
（澤圭(たくけい)）は… 速い！
S-So fast! The State of Wei Army has changed formations again!
また魏国軍の陣形が変わる
（尾平(びへい)）アア… やべえよ
This ain't good!
They finished making their formation before the charge reached them!
突入より先に
陣が完成しちまった！
（魏兵たち）エイッ！
ンフッ…
ぶつかるぞ！
They're gonna collide!
（麃公）ハアーッ！
（魏兵たち）ウワーッ！
Even Wu Qing will be surprised by this.
これには呉慶さんも びっくりです
麃公将軍の武力は
呉慶の予測のはるかに上をいきます
General Biao Gong's military power is far above what Wu Qing had anticipated.
何といっても あの方は
私と五分の武力の持ち主ですから
However, that man only wields half the military might that I do.
And...
そして 率いる軍の強さは
王騎軍より 少々 上
the strength of the army he's leading is a bit greater than the Wang Qi Army.
陣形の１つや２つは消し飛びますよ
He would scatter one or two of our formations.
しかし これからの呉慶の動きも
麃公将軍は予測できない
However...
General Biao Gong cannot predict what Wu Qing's next moves will be.
Call and Zhu Gui and Ma Gui. It's time to hunt.
朱鬼(しゅき)と麻鬼(まき)を呼べ　狩りの時間だ
（じい）はっ！
Yes, sir!
Are you beginning to understand?
（王騎）
少しは分かってきましたか？
What "War is its generals" means?
“戦は武将のもの”と言った意味が
"War is its generals"?!
（壁(へき)）戦は武将のものだと？
だったら 俺たちは何だ？
Then what are we?!
死んでいった者たちは？
縛虎申(ばくこしん)の死は？
What are the dead?!
What is Fu Hushen's death?!
ふざけるな！
俺たちは戦っている！
Don't screw around! We're fighting!
Bi Unit!
壁隊！ 突撃態勢！
麃公将軍の援護に行く！
Charging formation!
We're going to back up General Biao Gong!
This is likely to be the final battle!
恐らく これが最後の合戦となる！
全員 死力を尽くせ！
Everyone, use everything you've got left!
Now we depart!
（馬のいななき）
出陣！
（壁）戦は
決して武将だけのものではないぞ！
War is absolutely not defined by its generals, General Wang Qi!
王騎将軍！
壁…
Bi...
My, my.
少々 早とちりしましたね 壁副官は
（信）えっ？
He's really jumped to conclusions, hasn't he? Aide Bi...
（王騎）なぜ麃公さんは これまで
無謀なほど軍を動かし続けたか
Why do you think Biao Gong has been moving his army so recklessly?
戦局を動かし続けたからこそ
呉慶は今 地理的有利の丘を下り
It is because the state of war has kept moving
and that Wu Gong has left the geographically advantageous hill and is now in front of us.
我らの前にいるのですよ
For the Qin Army soldiers that seemed to die meaninglessly in the beginning,
序盤 無駄死に見えた秦軍の兵も
in terms of Biao Gong's style, were noble sacrifices for the sake of victory.
麃公さん風に言えば
“勝利のための尊い犠牲”
Thousand-Man General Fu Hushen said the same thing...
縛虎申千人将も同じことを言ってた
But the one who sent out those sacrifices was none other than Biao Gong.
しかし その犠牲を出させたのは
ほかならぬ麃公
つまり 戦は…
So in other words, war...
Depends on the generals!
武将しだい
（王騎）そのとおり ンフフフッ…
Exactly.
Understand, youngster Xin?
いいですか？ 童 信
今 ここにある状況は―
The situation we currently stand at
全て あの２人が
勝つために描き 導いたもの
was all guided by those two in order to gain victory.
Just two people... created this huge war...?
（信）たった２人が
こんな でっけえ戦を…
そう それが…
Yes. That is...
what is known as a general!
“将軍”というものです
（信）将軍…
General...
（信･漂(ひょう)）俺たちは
天下最強の大将軍になるんだ！
We will become the greatest generals under the heavens!
Greatest generals under the heavens...
（信）天下の大将軍…
誰もが知ってる強(つえ)え英雄
Strong heroes whose names everyone knows...
なんとなく
そんなことしか分からずに―
Somehow, without knowing those things, I would always scream that...
いつも ほえてた
だけど 今は
少しだけ姿が見えるようになった
But... now I think I can see how it truly is.
Because of this huge man's words...
この大男の言葉で
General... Wang Qi.
王騎将軍…
That's right!
そうか 俺は さっきから…
For a while now...
“将軍”と話をしていたのか！
I've been talking with a general!
王騎将軍
馬を１頭 貸してくれ …ください
General Wang Qi. Please, lend me a horse!
ほう… あなたも行くのですか？
Are you going as well?
この私との会話は そうそう
できるものではありませんよ
As I said in my speech, it won't amount to much of anything.
That's definitely true, but...
確かに そりゃそうだけど…
大将首が見えてんのに
行かない手はない！
if the head of a Great General is in sight, there's no way I could not act!
ンフッ…
（信）澤さん 頼む！
（澤圭）えっ？
Mr. Ze, take this.
（信）副将の首だ
（澤圭）アアッ…
It's the Vice General's head.
預けたぜ！ ハッ！
Hold onto it for me!
（山和(さんか)）
あのガキ また行っちまったぞ
That kid... left again.
（尾平）信…
Xin...
（羌瘣(きょうかい)）あいつは何なんだ？
（尾到(びとう)）えっ？
Who is that guy?
（尾平）見たまんまのバカだけど
Well, he's an idiot. Just like how he looks.
天下の大将軍になるんだとよ
ハハハッ…
But he's gonna become the greatest general under the heavens.
Greatest general under the heavens...
（羌瘣）天下の大将軍…
So he's a great idiot.
大バカだな
おらー！
（魏兵たち）ウワーッ！
暴れ回る猛牛をしとめるのに
いきなり頭を狙うことはない
The way to bring down a raging bull is not to immediately aim for the head.
Wei is changing formations again.
（騰(とう)）魏の陣形が また動く
（騰）うん？ これは なんと…
Oh my...
Against General Biao Gong's rush,
麃公将軍の突進に対し
防御を厚くするかと思いきや―
I thought he would widen his defenses.
But he has moved the inner-troops to the sides.
奥は左右に開いた
（王騎）フフフフッ… 呉慶さん
That Wu Qing. I knew his head would not be taken so easily.
やはり簡単に首は
取らせていただけないようですねえ
麃公軍の突破力のからくりに
気づいていらっしゃる
It seems he's realized the strength of the Biao Gong Army's rushing force.
（麃公軍兵Ａ）
右方！ 戦車隊が寄せてくるぞ！
Right side!
The Chariot Corps are approaching!
From the left as well! Here they come!
（麃公軍兵Ｂ）
左方も同様！ 来るぞ！
麃公将軍ではなく
その配下を襲う？
It's not General Biao Gong he's attacking, but his subordinates?
That aberrant charge with the general taking the lead himself...
大将自ら先頭を行くという
常軌を逸した あの突撃
敵は必ず先頭の１騎を狙います
The enemy is sure to aim for the head horse.
当然です　その１騎さえ討てば
戦が終わるのですから
It's only natural.
Seeing how if that horse is taken down, the war is over.
But they can't beat him.
しかし
討てないんですよ その１騎が
That one horse
standing in front of General Biao Gong means he is standing in front of the Biao Gong Army...
麃公将軍の前に立つということは
麃公軍の前に立つということ
将が先に立つことで―
The general standing in front means the whole army's morale is boosted to the utmost
極限まで高ぶった全軍の闘気が
一丸となって襲いかかる
and it attacks as one.
敵兵は皆 この気にあてられ
恐怖で身動きが取れなくなるのです
The enemy soldiers are affected by this spirit.
And cannot move out of fear.
That power of that charge which is easily splitting apart the enemy...
敵中を
やすやすと分け行く あの突破力
麃公自身の武力も もちろんですが
Biao Gong's power alone is great of course,
but with them following after their leader, with little likelihood of him being killed,
主(あるじ)を討たれまいと
あとに続いている―
麃公軍の兵の存在が大きいんですよ
the presence of the Biao Gong Army's soldiers is quite large.
One would not be going too far to say
彼らの放つ重圧こそ―
that the pressure they exude is the source of the Biao Gong Army's strength.
麃公軍の強さの源と言っても
過言ではないほどね
I see. Sensing that, Wu Qing split his army into two flanks.
なるほど　そのことを察した呉慶は
軍を左右に分けた
Yes. He has narrowed his target to the soldiers in back.
そう　彼は
標的を後ろの兵たちに絞りました
Crush them to a pulp!
すりつぶせ
（兵士）ウワッ！
It looks like he's shaved some off.
（騰）削られだしましたな
（王騎）士気の高さは
あくまで主を守るため
The height of the morale is created utterly for the reason of protecting the leader.
自らが狙われると
やはり素の力しか出せませんね
If he's targeted himself, he can only use his own natural power.
Biao Gong. If you continue in this way,
麃公さん あなた このままでは―
you will end up alone in a sea of the Wei Army, I'm afraid.
魏軍の海の中に
ひとりになってしまいますよ
Shit!
（尚鹿(しょうかく)）くそ！ これは
いくら何でも突破はムリだ！ 壁
No matter what we try here, a breakthrough is impossible, Bi!
We only have a hundred mounted solders!
俺たちは100騎といないんだ！
Forget aiding the Biao Gong Army,
麃公将軍の援護どころか
敵陣に入った途端に なぶり殺しだ
we'll be killed the moment we enter the enemy's formation!
Just trust me and come along, Shang Lu!
俺を信じて ついてこい！ 尚鹿
When we saw the enemy from above, I realized something.
丘の上から敵を見下ろしたとき
気づいたことがある
Even if it is Wu Qing's main army, with these numbers
いくら呉慶の本軍といえど この数
動きの鈍い隊が いくつかあった
そこを狙っていけば…
there were many units that could not move quickly.
We just need to target them!
ここから入るぞ！
We'll enter from here!
何だ？ こいつら　弱いな
（壁）このまま進めば…
What's with these guys? They're weak.
If we keep this up...
So you're trying to only target the weak?!
（武将Ａ）
器用に弱いとこばかり狙いよって…
Come on! I'm different from the others!
来い！
わしは ほかのヤツらとは違うぞ！
（信）すげえぜ 壁！
This is awesome, Bi!
王騎将軍に借りた この馬
飛ぶように速(はえ)え！
This horse that General Wang Qi lent me!
It's so fast it feels like it's flying!
（壁）ついてこい 信！
Come with me, Xin!
麃公軍を挟み込んでいる左の軍に
食らいつくぞ！
Crash through the left army that's attacking the Biao Gong Army!
（信）おう！ 壁千人将！
Got it, Thousand-Man General Bi!
The forces of the Qin Army has halved!
（武将Ｂ）秦国軍 勢い半減！
There is likely less than 3,000 remaining!
残り およそ3,000弱！
戦車隊が左に合流！
Chariot Corps, join the left!
我が軍 更に優勢！
Give our army further dominance!
（朱鬼）
お呼びでしょうか？ 呉慶さま
You called, Lord Wu Qing?
（呉慶）程なく麃公軍は壊滅し
麃公は孤立する
Before long, the Biao Gong Army will be wiped out.
And Biao Gong will be left alone.
Hunt his head and bring down the curtain on this war,
首を狩り 戦の幕を下ろしてまいれ
朱鬼 麻鬼
Zhu Gui, Ma Gui.
（朱鬼）お安いご用です
As good as done, sir.
ドリャー！
（魏兵たち）ウワーッ！
He got through!
（尚鹿）抜けた！
They're not even resisting!
手応えねえな！ 弱いぞ こいつら
These guys are so weak!
I just targeted the area that seemed weak.
（壁）
弱そうな所を狙っているだけだ
If you get caught up in the moment, you'll be killed, Xin!
調子づくと やられるぞ 信
Look, Bi!
（尚鹿）見ろ！ 壁
It's the Biao Gong Army!
（信）麃公軍だ！
よし！
Okay!
（騰）ところで 殿
別用で通りすがっただけとはいえ
By the way, my lord.
Although we were just passing by on other business,
このまま待機で
よろしいのですか？
would it be not apt to take this opportunity to intervene?
十分でしょう
This is quite enough.
我々が丘の上にいるだけで
Just by being atop this hill,
魏軍には
大きな牽制(けんせい)になっていますから
we are considerably restraining the Wei Army.
Also...
それに
見せていただきたいではないですか
Would you not like to see it for yourself?
新興勢力の実力を…
The true capability of these emerging powers?
（貂(てん)）新興勢力？
（政(せい)）そうだ
Emerging powers?
Yes.
Up until now in the State of Qin, there were only the two factions of Lü Shi and Jie Shi,
今まで呂氏(りょし) 竭氏(けつし)の２派しか
いなかった秦国に生まれた新しい力
but new powers have been born.
That is one faction led by Changwenjun.
それが 昌文君(しょうぶんくん)を筆頭とした一派だ
大王直属の一派が新興勢力ってのも
なんだかなぁ
So a faction working directly under the king is an emerging power? What's with that?
それが現実だ
That's reality.
Their size compared to that of Lü Shi is like a baby to an adult.
大きさは呂氏と比べれば
赤子と大人ほど開きがある
（政）
だが 俺が実権を取るには―
But in order for me to gain real power,
it is indispensable for the Changwenjun faction to gain strength together with me.
俺と共に 昌文君の一派も
強大になることが必須なのだ
文官の先頭に立つのは昌文君
Changwenjun is the official standing at its helm.
そして 武の方面で
先頭に立つべきは副官の壁
And the one leading the field of battle is Aide Bi.
It is because of that that it's necessary for Bi to direct forces in this war.
そのためにも
壁は この戦で力を示す必要がある
チェッ…
そこはウソでも信って言ってくれよ
Ya know, even if it's not true, could you say that Xin is doing that?
まあ 初陣だし そこまで
期待してないかもしれないけどさ
Well, it's his first campaign.
I guess we can't hope for that much, huh?
ここだ！ 行くぞ！
（信たち）オーッ！
Here it is! Let's go!
左方向より秦国軍の騎馬隊 出現！
麃公軍とは別の騎馬隊です！
A State of Qin Army of mounted unit has appeared from the left!
It is a separate mounted unit from the Biao Gong Army!
What?!
なに？
They seem to be attacking the right army from the exterior!
（武将Ｂ）右軍の外側から
仕掛けるもよう！ 数は100未満！
There are less than 100 of them!
All right!
よっしゃ！
今 助けてやるぞ 麃公軍！
We're here to help you, Biao Gong Army!
待て 信！ 行く必要はない
（信）えっ？
Wait, Xin!
There's no need for us to go!
あっ…
新手の騎馬隊 仕掛けてきません！
The new mounted unit is not attacking!
They are still running parallel to the right!
いまだ右側を併走中！
（呉慶）う～む…
ンフッ…
Why, Bi?!
（信）なんでだよ？ 壁
なんで攻撃しねえんだ？
Why aren't we attacking?!
せっかく援護に来たのに！
We came all the way here to be backup, didn't we?
If we attack with these numbers, we'll be defeated!
（壁）
この数で戦っても 我らは敗れる！
We should continue running parallel
それよりも このまま併走して
心理効果を与えるほうが援護になる
and give them backup psychologically!
Psychologically?
心理効果？
（壁）挟み込みだ
They're stuck in between!
With the enemy approaching from the front, sides, or behind,
前後や左右
両側から敵に迫られると―
our soldiers receive a psychological strain and lose morale.
兵は心理的重圧を受け
士気が下がる
それで麃公軍は苦戦している
Because of that the Biao Gong Army is in a tough fight.
だが 今は我々と麃公軍で
魏の軍を挟み込む形にもなっている
But now, with the Biao Gong Army and us,
we surround the Wei Army as well!
There may be few of us,
少数ではあるが 多少なりとも
魏軍に重圧がかかっているはずだ
but we should still be putting pressure on the Wei Army!
General Wang Qi said that the Biao Gong Army is stronger than the Wang Qi Army...
王騎将軍は
麃公軍が王騎軍よりも強いと言った
Then this indirect backup should be plenty!
ならば
この間接的援護で十分なはずだ
To the left!
（麃公）左じゃ！
Understood!
（部下）
御意！ 左軍をたたきつぶせー！
Crush the left army!
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
ウワーッ！
麃公軍が攻勢に転じた！
General Biao Gong has gone on the offensive!
All right!
よし！
Aw, awesome!
おお すげえ！ さすが麃公軍！
I knew that Biao Gong Army was something!
（壁）信！
Xin?!
ハアーッ！
（魏兵たち）ヒイッ…
Pressure of armies, huh?
（朱鬼）軍の重圧か
武将狩りの名を持つ我らに
そんな まやかしは通用せぬ
We, the hunters of military commanders,
cannot let such shallow trickery pass by!
（麻鬼）俺が馬の首を飛ばそう
（朱鬼）では 俺がヤツの首を取る
I'll send those horses' heads flying.
Then I will take the humans' heads.
We will split the credit 50-50.
（麻鬼）手柄は半々だぞ
（朱鬼）フフフッ… 分かっている
Got it.
待て　１騎来る
Wait. One horse is coming.
ハアーッ！
There's no time.
時間がないぞ
（麻鬼）分かっている
I know.
フン…
（信）ヘヘヘッ… 思ったとおりだ
Just as I thought.
まあまあ強えじゃねえか
You're pretty strong, ain'cha?!
飛ばしてきた甲斐(かい)があったぜ
ヘヘヘッ…
It was worth it to rush ahead.
あっ…
（じい）どうした？
What is it?!
Ma Gui is now in combat with one mounted solider that appeared from the flank!
（武将Ｂ）脇より現れた
１騎の騎馬と麻鬼さまが―
交戦中です！
（じい）なに？
What?!
（信）クッ… くそ！
Shit!
２人とも斬ろうと思ってたのに
こいつ１人もヤバイ！
I thought I'd be able to cut them both down!
But just this one guy is really good!
急げ 麻鬼！ 来るぞ！
Hurry, Ma Gui! They're coming!
こいつ 雑になってきやがった
This guy's... getting sloppy!
死ねー！
Die!
（信）ハアッ！
ドリャー！
なんだと！
What?!
おらぁ！
Biao Gong!
麃公！
ウリャー！
General Biao Gong!
麃公将軍！
Lord Zhu Gui and Ma Gui have been killed!
（武将Ｂ）
朱鬼さま 麻鬼さま 討ち死に！
Biao Gong has broken through the final defensive barrier!
麃公 最終防壁を突破！
Oh... Oh-no!
い… いかん… 麃公が来るぞ
Biao Gong is coming!
All units! Battle positions!
全軍 臨戦態勢を取れ！
麃公が来るぞ！
Biao Gong is coming!
麃公が来るぞー！
Do not lose your presence of mind!
（じい）ええい うろたえるな！
We have twice their numbers here!
ここには
ヤツらの倍以上の兵力がある！
And the strategy Lord Wu Qing has, which is no fewer than one hundred strategies, will soon be unleashed!
そして これより繰り出される
呉慶さまの軍略は100を下らぬ！
We shall be victorious!
勝つのは我らだ！
（魏兵たち）オーッ！
Lord Wu Qing, your orders...
呉慶さま ご指示を
By my plan, there will be no need to clash with Biao Gong, who has relied on luck and momentum.
じいの策としましては―
運と勢いに乗った麃公に
あえて つきあう必要はなく
I, Jii, believe we should return temporarily to the hill and reorganize
一度 丘に戻り 立て直し
じっくり
秦軍を滅ぼしてはと思いますが…
and slowly break down the Qin Army. But...
（呉慶）フフフフッ…
（じい）呉慶さま？
Lord Wu Qing?
これだから やめられぬのだ 戦は！
This is why we cannot stop now.
This is war!
（麃公）オリャー！
オリャー！
（麃公）丸城(がんじょう)の皆殺しから始まり
これまで 両軍 多くの血を流した
It started with the slaughter at Wan Castle.
And now much blood from both armies has spilled.
呉慶…
Wu Qing.
We finally meet.
（麃公）ようやく会えたのぅ
フン…
手出し無用ぞ
There is no need to interfere.
フン…
General Biao Gong...!
麃公将軍…
One on one? That's insane! What are they planning?
一騎打ち？
バカな… どういうことだ？
武力で
呉慶が麃公将軍にかなうはずがない
In armed combat, Wu Qing should not be a match for General Biao Gong.
Is it a trap?
ワナか？
ンフフッ…
ハアッ！
ハアーッ！
michi wa tsuzuku yume wo oimotome
路は続く　夢を追い求め
The path goes on, chasing after a dream.
nozomu saki ni kimi no ashita wa aru no?
望む先に　君の明日はあるの？
Will your tomorrow be at the place my hopes lead?
kizutsuite kokoro mo mada kawaku nara
傷ついて　心もまだ渇くなら
If I get hurt and my heart is still thirsty,
koko e kite nando demo utau kara
ここへ来て何度でも歌うから
I'll come here and sing as many times as it takes.
owari naki tatakai no naka de
終わりなき戦いの中で
In this endless battle
kimi wa tsuyoku kawaru
君は強く変わる
You change to become stronger.
kono sora wo kirisaita ikazuchi wa kimi
この空を切り裂いた　雷は君
The lightning that cut apart this sky is you.
osore wo koete tachimukau hikari no ya hashiridasu
恐れを超えて立ち向かう　光の矢　走りだす
The arrow of light that overcomes fear faces forward and shoots forth.
tsukamu sadame shinjitsuzukeru no...
掴む　運命　信じ続けるの…
I'll grab onto the destiny I've always believed in...
～♪
Preview
麃公！
Biao Gong!
Wu Qing!
呉慶！
They are cool-headedly surrounded.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
冷徹に取り囲み もはや逃がさぬ
They can no longer run away!
So burn away that encirclement!
ならば その包囲 燃やし尽くす！
Wise General VS Courageous General
End
次回 “知将 対 猛将”
Next time,